(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-30T22:32:34.678417",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
高鳴る心臓に
With a pounding heart,
祈りを乗せて
carrying my prayers,
曖昧な夢を描く
I draw an indefinite dream.
幻想は想像のまま
Illusions remain as imaginations,
終われないんだ
they can't just end here.
みんなー！今日も会いに来てくれてありがとー！
Everyone! Thank you for coming to see me today!
答えを永遠と探し続けて
Endlessly searching for an answer,
何者かになりたくて
wishing to become somebody,
燦々と降る夕立を
I merely gazed at
ただ眺めた
the heavily falling evening shower.
優しく寄り添って
Gently nestling close,
心が晴れるのなら
if it can clear your heart,
翼が生えたような気がして
I feel as if wings have grown,
いつだって隣にいるから
because I will always be right beside you.
だって言葉紡いで歌うことが
Because weaving words into song
わたしの運命だ
is my destiny.
世界にあふれた虚しささえも
Overwriting even the emptiness
上書きして
that overflows in this world,
路地裏に咲いた花のように
like a flower blooming in a back alley,
願いを照らす
illuminating wishes,
小さな光に憧れて
yearning for a small light.
名前を持たない歌なんて
A song without a name
神様は認めてくれない
won't be recognized by God.
一つ一つ枯れない花のように
One by one, like flowers that never wither,
昨日の自分にさよならして
saying goodbye to yesterday's self,
溢れた涙
the overflowing tears,
上手に笑えなくてもいいかな
is it okay even if I can't smile well?
だって理想は遠ざかってくばかり
Because my ideals only keep drifting away,
もう散々だよ
it's already terrible.
どれだけ手を伸ばして叫んだって
No matter how much I reach out and shout,
届かないの
it doesn't reach.
望めばいつか叶うはずって信じてる
I believe if I wish, it will come true someday,
どうか歌よ響いて
please, song, echo out!
あぁ心臓の鼓動が今日も五月蠅い
Ah, my heartbeat is so noisy again today,
行き止まりばっか足が竦んで立てないよ
Only dead ends, my legs freeze and I can't stand.
行き詰まりばっか 足がすくんで
I keep running into dead ends, my feet freeze up,
立ってないよ
and I can't even stand.
音のない世界から君を見つけて 連れ出すんだ
From a soundless world, I'll find you and bring you out!
言葉紡いで 歌うことが わたしの運命だ
Weaving words and singing is my destiny.
世界にありふれた 虚しささえも 上書きして
Overwriting even the emptiness that fills the world,
路地裏に咲いた花のように 願いを照らす
like a flower blooming in a back alley, illuminating wishes,
小さな光に憧れて
longing for that small light.
君の歌姫になれたらいいな
I hope I can become your diva.
okey dokey 返事はいいけど
Okey dokey, your response is fine,
冗談なら笑えないよ
but if it's a joke, I can't laugh.
渋滞 曖昧 どっちを向いちゃうの
Congestion, ambiguity, which way are you looking?
蜃気楼に手を伸ばした
I reached my hand out to a mirage.
微熱のような夢物語
A dream story like a slight fever,
そんな光は見ない振りをしていた
I pretended not to see such a light.
ざわめく鼓動 まだ行かないで
My throbbing heartbeat, don't go just yet,
幻じゃ嫌だよ
I don't want it to be an illusion.
私を奪って
Take me away!
魅惑の dancing dancing night
Fascinating dancing dancing night,
広がって収まんない universe
an expanding, boundless universe.
君の表情は 私の森羅万象を
Your expression might rewrite
書き換えちゃうかも 責任重大ね
my whole world, that's a big responsibility.
一切合切 dance dance dance
Everything, dance dance dance,
we are dancing reed
夢中になって絡み合った ゼログラビティ
Absorbed and intertwined in zero gravity,
構わず dance dance dance
regardless, dance dance dance,
just a dance just a dance
声は闇に預けたまま
Leaving my voice entrusted to the darkness,
目を覚ましても離れないで
don't leave even if you wake up.
maybe needy 正気じゃないのよ
Maybe needy, I'm not in my right mind,
体温が忘れられない
I can't forget your body heat.
誰彼そんなんじゃないから
It's not just anyone,
独り占めして euphoria
monopolize me, euphoria.
気にしてない様な言葉は装飾で
Words sounding indifferent are just decoration,
メイクのようには流せない
I can't wash them away like makeup.
360°偽りだって 隠し切れぬような
Even if 360° is fake, as if unable to hide it,
私に構って
pay attention to me.
嬉しいなんて crazy crazy love
Saying I'm happy is crazy crazy love,
摩天楼から連れさらって
snatch me away from the skyscraper.
君の表情は
Your expression
私の深層心理を
swaps my deep inner psychology,
すり替えちゃうのよ 責任重大ね
that's a big responsibility.
過ぎ去ったネオン 残像 shooting star
Passed neon, lingering image, shooting star.
グライダーみたいに漂えば
If I drift like a glider,
幸も不幸もなかった
there was neither happiness nor unhappiness.
指先でまた君を探している
I'm searching for you again with my fingertips,
その声を聴かせてよ
let me hear that voice.
私に構って 教えさせてよ 恋の先を
Pay attention to me, teach me what comes after love!
広がって収まんない universe
An expanding, boundless universe,
君の存在は 私の将来までも
your existence steps right into
踏み込んだのよ 付き合ってよね
my future, so stay with me, okay?
一切合切 dance dance dance
Everything, dance dance dance,
we are dancing reed
夢中になって絡み合った ゼログラビティ
Absorbed and intertwined in zero gravity,
構わず dance dance dance
regardless, dance dance dance,
just a dance just a dance
声は闇に預けたまま
Leaving my voice entrusted to the darkness,
目を覚ましても離れないで
don't leave even if you wake up.
みんなー！
Everyone!
今日はお誕生日ライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you so much for coming to my birthday live stream today!
コメントも見えてるよー！
I can see your comments too!
最初に聴いてもらったのが『Diva』『Dancing Reed』でしたー！
First up, you listened to "Diva" and "Dancing Reed"!
えー、この2つの曲は、フェスと、あと去年のね、ドラマの主題歌に使っていただいた曲で、すごく思い出に残っているので、最初に2曲歌ってみようかなと思って選びました！
Umm, these two songs were used for the festival and last year's drama theme song. They hold so many great memories for me, so I picked them to sing first!
アクセス、そして今回はですね
And today,
『ときのそら お披露目誕生日2026』...
welcome to "Tokino Sora Unveiling Birthday 2026"...
ときのそらおじゃないよ、ときのそらだよ！
It's not "Tokino Sora-o", it's Tokino Sora!
えー
Uh...
みんなのつぶやきを待ってるので たくさんつぶやいてほしいな
I'm waiting for everyone's tweets, so please tweet a lot!
トレンドに入るといいなー
I hope it trends!
ねー！
Right?
そして 今回のテーマは 8周年を象徴する「無限」をモチーフに
And this time's theme, taking "infinity" as a motif to symbolize the 8th anniversary,
宇宙や星をステージに散りばめて 中毒性のあるビート
with space and stars scattered across the stage, combined with addictive beats
リズムの曲で絡めた デジタルパルスライブです！
and rhythmic songs, is a Digital Pulse Live!
こちらね 大きな天球が曲によってどう変わるのかを見ていてください
Please keep an eye on how this huge celestial sphere changes depending on the song!
そしてね 今年のあんもんは 5つなので
And also, this year there are five Anmons, so...
くるくる回転してます くるくるくるくる…
They're spinning round and round. Round and round...
そして 空にはソラザウルスもいるよ！
And look, Sorazaurus is up in the sky too!
ソラザウルスはね なんとね 炎を出せるようになりました！
Sorazaurus can actually breathe fire now!
ぼーっ！
*Whoosh!*
あんきももね ちゃんとあんきも座もあるんですけど
Ankimo is here too, there's even an Ankimo constellation,
見えるかな？
can you see it?
もちろん あと今年も新衣装のお披露目や 告知したゲストと
Of course, look forward to the new outfit reveal this year, the guests we announced,
どんな曲をお披露目するのかを楽しみに待っててくださいね！
and what songs we'll be performing!
そして 次に行く前に プチお披露目 最初にしちゃいましょう！
And before we move on, let's do a quick mini-reveal first!
カメラさん 上 向いてください！
Camera person, please point upwards!
はい！というわけで
Yay! And with that...
新しい くらげヘア！新髪型お披露目です！
It's my new jellyfish hair! A new hairstyle reveal!
それでは早速 ゲストパートに行ってみよう！
Now then, let's jump straight into the guest segment!
「かわいい」ありがとう！おおー「かわいい」ありがとう！
Thank you for calling it cute! Ooh, thank you for "cute"!
シロぐみさんもいっぱいコメントしてってね！
Shirogumi fans, leave lots of comments too!
最初のゲストは… この人です！
Our first guest is... this person!
[GUEST 電脳少女シロ]
[Guest: Dennou Shoujo Siro]
星の降る夜に
On a night when stars fall,
ダンスダンスだって 夜は夜でラクチン
Even dance, dance in the night is easygoing.
今夜はいやに星のアイモライトが いやに眩しいから
Tonight, the starlight is so terribly dazzling...
街のネオンカラーも
The city's neon colors, too,
文字通り横目に 人間とふたり
as expected, we glance past them, just you and me.
しどけないくらい クラクラしちゃう 心惑わすから
I feel dizzy to the point of helplessness, confusing my heart...
あなただけ 君だけ
Only you, only you,
夜に散らかして 駆ける
scattered across the night, we run.
見つめあうあなたの表情 照らして 明星ギャラクティカ
Illuminating your expression as we gaze at each other, Venus Galactica.
見上げた夜空の彼方 宇宙は散らばって光る
Far across the night sky we look up at, the universe scatters and shines.
プカプカ踊り踊って 孤独ごと消し去って
Dancing floatingly, erasing even our loneliness,
ふたりの銀河で 愛の手が 導く 向いて
In our galaxy, the hand of love guides us to face each other.
恋はギャラクティカ
Love is Galactica!
あぁ 同じペースで泳ぎだすベースメント 宵と宵で繋ぐ浅い 一度きりのダンス
Ah, swimming out at the same pace in the basement, a shallow, one-time dance joining dusk to dusk.
あなたとわたしの旅立つ星の行方は 何光年先を探した
Where is the star we're journeying to? We searched light-years ahead.
結ぶオリオンの赤い星 真っ赤に燃えるから
The red star connecting Orion burns so brightly red...
今夜だけ 君だけ 踊りましょう 夜はあんまりの寂漠だから
Just for tonight, just with you, let's dance, because the night is far too lonely.
見つめあうあなたの表情 隠して 明星ギャラクティカ
Hiding your expression as we gaze at each other, Venus Galactica.
そわつく危険な気持ちが 満ちだして探りあうから
As this restless, dangerous feeling swells and we probe each other...
生まれたままの衝動 隠して 明星ギャラクティカ
Hiding our raw, natural impulses, Venus Galactica.
あなたと言葉が 解けて 解ける
You and words melt and dissolve...
惑わされるほどほんとのこと 言わないで
Don't tell me truths that bewilder me so much.
最後の夜は あなたと星と星が もっと解けて 君はギャラクティカ
On this final night, you and star after star melt further... You are Galactica!
いつだって愛のワンティカ
Always, the wantica of love!
ヴァンパイア ヴァンパイア
Vampire, Vampire
はい！というわけで最初のゲストは...
Alright! So our first guest is...
シロちゃんだよ〜！
Shiro-chan~!
こんにちは〜！ときの...シロです！
Hello~! Tokino... Shiro here!
ときのシロになっちゃった！
You became Tokino Shiro!
本当に今日、そらちゃん...お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Really, today, Sora-chan... Happy Birthday!
ありがと〜！
Thank you~!
すごいね、格好...
That's an amazing... outfit...
あ、そらちゃんという歌姫に...お祝いできると聞いて...出せるものは全部出していこうと思います！
Ah, hearing that I could celebrate with a songstress like Sora-chan, I thought I'd pull out all the stops!
そ、そういうことだったんだ！
S-So that's what it was!
待って！これで...チャンネルBANされちゃったら...
Wait! If my channel gets banned for this...
そんなことない！ごめんなさい！
No way! I'm sorry!
大丈夫！大丈夫だから！
It's okay! It's okay!
胸が苦しくなってきました...
My chest is starting to feel tight...
大丈夫！？
Are you okay?!
そらちゃん、クラゲさんには...毒針があると聞きます...
Sora-chan, I hear jellyfish... have venomous stingers...
毒針！？
Stingers?!
毒針をぜひ、頭でゴツンとシロに刺していただけませんか？
Would you please sting Shiro on the head with your venomous stinger?
ゴツン！
Bonk!
うっ...うっ...
Ugh... ugh...
倒れ...倒れちゃう！
She's collapsing... falling over!
効いてきました...
It's taking effect...
効いてきた！？
It worked?!
みなさん、そらちゃんは...変わりました。毒針を持った女に変わったんです！
Everyone, Sora-chan... has changed. She changed into a woman with a venomous stinger!
で、でも！そう、私強くなったから！
B-But! Yeah, because I got stronger!
そらちゃんは毒針が持ちたくて可愛いクラゲヘアになったんですか？
Did Sora-chan want a venomous stinger so much that she got a cute jellyfish hair style?
いやいやいや！私、やっぱアイドルと言えばこういう可愛い髪型の人が多いかなと思って...
No, no, no! I thought, when you think of idols, there are many people with cute hairstyles like this...
そういうアイドルっぽい髪型にしたいなと思ってたんだよね！
So I wanted to try an idol-like hairstyle!
そらちゃんって聞いてください！もうアイドルでしかないし歌姫でしかないのに...
Sora-chan, please listen! Even though you're pure idol and pure songstress...
『DIVA』っていう曲も出してるけど、今もアイドルであらんと...
You even released a song called 'DIVA', yet you're still striving to be an idol...
努力してくれる姿がもう大好きで、食べたいくらい...
I love seeing you work so hard, I could just eat you up...
食べちゃうの！？
Eat me?!
シナモロールみたいですね！見てカメラさん、見て見て！
She looks like Cinnamoroll! Look camera-san, look look!
これはシナモロール...シナモロール...
This is Cinnamoroll... Cinnamoroll...
食べられてる...食べられてる...
I'm being eaten... being eaten...
良い匂い...
Smells good...
はい、ということで！今日はBANしない発言を心掛けていきます！
Alright, so! Today I'll try my best to avoid making statements that get us banned!
もうすでに結構シロちゃんワールド炸裂してますけど...
You're already blasting your Shiro-chan World pretty hard though...
あの...なんかこんな...大好きなそらちゃんのこんな場にそらともさんたちと...一緒に呼んでもらえると思わなくて...
Um... I never thought I'd be invited to a place like this with my beloved Sora-chan and the Soratomo...
ありがとう！
Thank you!
3年ぶりだよ！
It's been 3 years!
3年ぶりの...元カノです！
The ex-girlfriend from 3 years ago!
元カノじゃない！
Not ex-girlfriend!
そらともさん！一緒に...一緒に...
Soratomo-san! Together... together...
独り占めしないので愛でていきましょう！
I won't keep her to myself, so let's cherish her together!
あの、今日はそらともさんに、あのシロの来た意味を分からせたいと思います！
Um, today I want to make Soratomo-san understand the meaning of Shiro coming here!
そらちゃん、立ってください！
Sora-chan, please stand up!
はい！
Okay!
3、2、1...
3, 2, 1...
バニーガールで...
Bunny girl...
このスクショでいいの？ねぇ？
Is this screenshot okay? Hey?
千手観音...
A Thousand-Armed Kannon...
そらちゃん新衣装のバニー衣装プレゼントしに来ました〜！
I came to gift Sora-chan a new bunny outfit~!
ありがとう〜！
Thank you~!
どうですか〜？
How is it~?
可愛いよ！バニーガールも可愛いよ〜！
It's cute! The bunny girl look is so cute too~!
うさぎさんって万年発情してるので、ちょっとはぁはぁしてもらって...
Rabbits are perpetually in heat, so if you could pant a little...
可愛い〜！
So cute~!
私もしっぽあるよ〜！
I have a tail too~!
あ！そうだよ！そらちゃんと言えば...あ、しっぽは...
Ah! That's right! Speaking of Sora-chan... Ah, the tail is...
そう、ちょっと...押してもいいですか？
Yeah, can I... press it?
いいよ！全然！
Sure! Go ahead!
あ！大変！何、シロ...発情が止まらないの...
Ah! Oh no! What, Shiro... can't stop going into heat...
ヤバい！
Oh no!
そろそろお家に帰ります！
I'll be heading home soon!
帰っちゃうの！？
You're leaving?!
はい！月からみんなを見守っています！このあとも楽しんでね！
Yes! I'll watch over everyone from the moon! Enjoy the rest of the show!
楽しんでね〜！ありがとう〜！
Enjoy~! Thank you~!
ほんとに...あ、なんか出てきた...
Really... Ah, something came out...
ちょっと！帰れてないよー！
Hey! You haven't left yet!
シロちゃんワールド炸裂で...楽しかったね！
Shiro-chan World exploded... That was fun!
なんだこれって言わないでね、みんな！ねぇ〜！
Don't say "what was that", everyone! Right?~
ねー！相変わらずのシロちゃんで私一緒に歌えてとっても楽しかったです！
Right~! Being the same old Shiro-chan, I had so much fun singing together!
マイペースだね！ねー、マイペースだよ！
So laid-back! Yeah, super laid-back!
私もしマイペースだから...いいコンビってことだ！
I'm laid-back too, so... that means we're a great duo!
というわけで！続いてのゲストにいきましょう！この人です！
And with that! Let me introduce the next guest! It's this person!
GUEST 緋月ゆい
[Guest: Hizuki Yui]
全部 全部 あんたのせいだ
It's all, all your fault.
反吐が出るくらいにウザったいわ
You're so annoying it makes me sick.
何かにすがって 諂って
Clinging to something, flattering...
期待したアタシが馬鹿だった
I was a fool for expecting anything.
ご機嫌伺いの八方美人
A two-faced flatterer trying to please everyone.
それ故にアンチな一生gimme
That's why you give me a lifetime of hate.
浅いキャパシティ 毎度おおきに
A shallow capacity, thanks a lot as always.
つまるところ人生ずっと地味
In short, your whole life is completely plain.
「憎々しい！」「痛々しい！」
"Detestable!" "Pathetic!"
無視出来ないのがいっそ腹立たしい
It's even more infuriating that I can't ignore it.
苛立たしい そろそろ飽きた自画自賛に
It's annoying, I'm sick of your self-praise.
(look around!)
ライクの反対はアパシー
The opposite of like is apathy,
≒繋がれた証
≒ proof of being connected.
切り離せない関係
An inseparable relationship,
逸らしてしまいたいわ
I just want to look away from it all.
これは所謂ヘイトスピーチ
This is what you'd call hate speech,
匿名性の声明を生命に乗せてんだ
Carrying anonymous declarations upon our very lives.
鳴り止まないサイレン 近づく度に痙攣
The endless sirens, spasms whenever they draw near.
赤信号にずっと従順です
Forever obedient to the red light.
大体 アナタのコト アタシ
Honestly, as for you, I...
ダイダイダイダイダイキライ
I really, really, really hate you!
omg 情けない 最早
OMG, so pathetic, at this point...
バイバイバイバイバイしたい
I want to say bye-bye-bye-bye-bye!
脳内も予測不能故に
Inside my head is so unpredictable...
解解解解解は無い
There's no solution, no answer at all.
どうだい？ アタシのコト アナタ
Well? As for me, have you...
ダイダイダイダイダイキライになった？
Come to really, really, really hate me too?
あぁ 百害あって一利ナシ nothing not see
Ah, all harm and zero benefit, nothing, not see.
もしタラレバ並べてもニコチンだし
Even listing "what ifs" is as addictive as nicotine.
i miss youって近付いた結末は凡ミス凡ミス
Approaching with "I miss you" ended in stupid mistake after mistake.
センキュー反面教師
Thank you, negative role model.
後味一生消えてくんないわ
This bad aftertaste won't disappear for the rest of my life.
よしよし いい子ね
There, there, good girl.
笑顔振り撒きパラパラ いい子ね
Scattering fake smiles everywhere, good girl.
だけど だけど その本性は？
But, but what's your true nature?
善悪の区別も付かないの？(笑) はぁ
Can't you even tell right from wrong? (laughs) *sigh*
減点方式で取り巻く環境に巻かれて
Swept up in an environment based on point deductions,
生涯痛い！痛い！痛い！も聴かれないわ！って
Crying "It hurts! It hurts!" all your life without anyone listening!
当然の報いに喰らっちゃった
Got hit by the retribution you deserved.
人は鏡なんです
People are mirrors of each other.
実のところ依存は両辺です
Truth is, dependence goes both ways.
シャットダウンしても付き纏う
Even if you shut down, it haunts you.
己の弱さが不甲斐ない
Frustrated by my own weakness.
全部 全部 あんたのせいに
Blaming it all, all on you,
反吐が出るくらいに止まんないわ
It won't stop to the point of making me sick.
いっその事 切り離せた方が 楽なのににな
It'd be so much easier if I could just cut you off.
大体 アナタのコト アタシ
Honestly, as for you, I...
ダイダイダイダイダイキライ
I really, really, really hate you!
omg 情けない 最早
OMG, so pathetic, at this point...
バイバイバイバイバイしたい
I want to say bye-bye-bye-bye-bye!
脳内も予測不能故に
Inside my head is so unpredictable...
解解解解解は無い
There's no solution, no answer at all.
どうだい？ アタシのコト アナタ
Well? As for me, have you...
ダイダイダイダイダイキライになった？
Come to really, really, really hate me too?
あぁ 百害あって一利ナシ nothing not see
Ah, all harm and zero benefit, nothing, not see.
もしタラレバ並べてもニコチンだし
Even listing "what ifs" is as addictive as nicotine.
i miss youって近付いた結末は凡ミス凡ミス
Approaching with "I miss you" ended in stupid mistake after mistake.
センキュー反面教師
Thank you, negative role model.
後味一生消えてくんないわ
This bad aftertaste won't disappear for the rest of my life.
イェーイ！
Yay!
どうもー！
Hello, everyone!
というわけでゲストの、ゆいちゃんです！
And so, our guest today is Yui-chan!
はい！改めましてNeo-Porte所属の緋月ゆいです！そらさん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Yes! Once again, I'm Hizuki Yui from Neo-Porte! Sora-san, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！来てくれて嬉しい！
Thank you so much! I'm so happy you came!
おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
1年ぶり！
It's been a whole year!
A whole year indeed!
いやね、去年はね、ちょっと残念ながらメッセージだけでね...
You know, last year, unfortunately, it was just a video message...
あの、去年は本当に申し訳ありませんでした！
Um, I'm so sorry about last year!
いやでもメッセージでもね、すごくみんな「うわぁ！」ってなってて嬉しかったですよ！
But even with just a message, everyone was like "Whoa!", so I was really happy!
すごいガラガラ声でね、去年は参加させていただいたんですけど...
My voice was super raspy when I joined last year, but...
今年はリベンジができてとっても嬉しいです！
I'm so happy I could get my revenge this year!
やったー！リベンジだー！
Yay! The revenge match!
呼んでいただいて嬉しいです！ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for inviting me!
こちらこそー！
The pleasure is mine!
今回の曲はね、私が選んだんですけども...
I was the one who chose today's song, and...
やっぱり、ゆいちゃんといえば格好いい声、というのが私の中で頭にあって、「格好いいよー！」と思って。
Whenever I think of you, Yui-chan, I think of your cool voice, and I was like "She's so cool!"
なので、このデュエットっていうのもあるので、この曲を是非一緒に歌いたい！と思って...
So since it's a duet song, I really wanted to sing it together with you...
嬉しい！お聞きしました！ありがとうございます！
I'm so happy! I heard about that! Thank you so much!
どうだったかな？
How was it performing it?
いや、あの、歌も超難しかったんですけど、
Well, the song was super difficult, but...
どちらかというとダンスが普段あんまりしないので...
More than that, since I don't usually dance much...
ちょっと、そらさんとダンスレッスンなどもやらせていただきましてですね、
So I even took dance lessons together with Sora-san,
本番に向けて準備してまいりました！
and prepared hard for the actual show!
でも振り覚えるのめちゃくちゃ早くてびっくりした！
But you learned the choreo super fast, I was amazed!
いやいや全然！恐縮でございます...
No, not at all! You flatter me...
ちょっとね、「あー！」って言いながら踊ってたの！
She was dancing while going "Ahhh!" in panic!
そうなんです！間奏でターンするところがあったんですけど、皆さん！
That's right! There was a part during the interlude where we turn around, everyone!
ターンが本当に体幹がなさすぎて、「あー！」って何回もよろけてですね...
I have such poor core balance that during the turns I kept stumbling like "Ahhh!"...
大変だったんですけど...
It was really tough, but...
いや、でも本番は完璧だったんじゃないの？
But wasn't it flawless during the actual show just now?
あ、良かったです！
Ah, what a relief!
いや、素晴らしいよ！
No, it was wonderful!
よかった、よろけなくて... めっちゃ頭で「よろけんじゃねぇ、よろけんじゃねぇ」と思いながら...
I'm so glad I didn't stumble... In my head I was like "Don't stumble, don't stumble!"...
意識してました。
I was so conscious of it.
もうそらさんが完璧なんで、ダンスが！
Because Sora-san's dancing is completely flawless!
だから隣に立つから私もしっかりしなきゃと思って... うまくいって良かったです！
So standing next to you, I felt I had to pull myself together... I'm so glad it went well!
まさかね、ダンスまでしてくれると思わなかったの。
I honestly didn't expect you to dance as well.
だから... えっ、本当ですか？
So... Oh, really?
誘った時に「ダンスもあるんですけど...」って言った時に...
When I invited you and mentioned, "There's a dance part too..."
「やだ」って言われるかなって思ったから...
I thought you'd say, "Oh no..."
いや、もう是非と思って！
No way, I really wanted to do it!
普段ね、こう右手でどうにかしてるんで...
Usually, I just manage somehow with my right hand...
手持ちマイクで右手でどうにか尺稼ぎしてたんですけど
Holding the mic and using my right hand to buy time,
今日はダンスに挑戦できたのが自分的にもすごい嬉しかったです。
but I was really happy I could challenge myself to dance today.
めちゃくちゃかっこよかった！
You were super cool!
いやいや、一緒に踊れて超嬉しかったんで。ありがとうございました！
No, no, I was super happy to dance together. Thank you so much!
こちらこそ！どうでしたか？
Same here! How was it?
どうだった？ かっこよかったでしょー！
How was it? Cool, right?
頑張ったぞー！
We worked hard!
頑張ったよー！
We sure did!
この後もまだライブがあるということなので、この後もぜひ頑張ってください！
There's still more of the live show coming up, so do your best for the rest of it!
頑張るよー！ 応援してます！ ありがとうー！
I will! I'm cheering for you! Thank you!
はい！ということで、癒月ちょこさんでした！
Alright! That was Yuzuki Choco!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much!
頑張ってねー！ ありがとうねー！ バイバーイ！
Do your best! Thank you! Bye-bye!
てやー！ てやー！
Te-ya! Te-ya!
よかったー！ 癒月ちゃんが来てくれました！
Glad that worked out! Yuzuki-chan came by!
癒月ちゃんって言ったの初めてかも。来てくれました！ 嬉しいねー！
Might be the first time I've called her Yuzuki-chan! She came! I'm so happy!
というわけで、あっという間なんだけど...私「というわけで」が口癖なんだな。今気づいちゃった。
So then, it went by in a flash... I just realized "So then" is my catchphrase.
ここからライブ後半戦です！
From here on is the second half of the live concert!
それでは5曲目、聞いてください。「モニタリング」
Now then, please listen to the 5th song, "Monitoring".
ねえあたし知ってるよ 君がひとり涙してるの
Hey, guess what, I know that you're all alone crying
知ってるよ ビクンビクン震えてさ 声もだだ漏れなんだわ
I know it, trembling bit by bit, your voice leaks right out
正直にいっちゃえばバレてるんだし いっちゃえばきてんの
Honestly speaking, your secret's out anyway, so come on over
フツフツ平気だよ みんな分かってないだけ mwah
It's totally fine, everyone else just doesn't get it, mwah!
もしもし
Hello?
ねえ 大丈夫？
Hey, are you okay?
うん 心配だから今からそっち行くね
Yeah, I'm worried about you, so I'm coming over now.
ねえあたし知ってるよ 君がひとり涙してるの
Hey, guess what, I know that you're all alone crying
知ってるよ グスングスン凹んでさ
I know it, sob-sobbing and feeling down,
弱音吐いてからいいんじゃない？
isn't it fine to vent your weakness?
朝が来るまで一緒コース
We're together until morning comes
もっと泣いたって 何度だって受け止めてあげる
Cry all you want, I'll embrace you again and again
もう我慢しないで いっぱい吐いてね mwah!
Don't hold it in anymore, spill it all out, mwah!
お願い 君が欲しいの
Please, I want you so bad
慰めさせて ベストフレンド 愛の才能で
Let me comfort you, best friend, with my knack for loving
泣いてくれるかい？
Won't you please cry for me?
君の辛い 抱きしめたい ねえいいでしょ？
I wanna hold your pain tight, say yes, okay?
分け合って 乗り越えたいんだっだったってば
I'm telling you, I wanna share it and overcome it together!
mwah! お願い 君が欲しいの
Mwah! Please, I want you so bad
笑い飛ばして ホップ ステップ ジャンプ 最高で
Laugh it off, hop, step, jump, the absolute best!
分けてくれるかい？ 君にはもう辛い思い
Won't you share it with me? Your dark thoughts
もうねえいいでしょ？
Aren't enough already, say yes, okay?
寄り添って 救いたいんだっだったってば
I'm telling you, I wanna stay close and save you!
見たい見たい見たい...の君の中
I wanna see inside of you
ねえあたし知ってるよ 君がひとり悔しがっての
Hey, guess what, I know you're all alone feeling frustrated
知ってるよ グスングスン終わるまで 君を絶対諦めない
I know it, until your sob-sobbing ends, I'll never give up on you
ねえあたし知ってるよ 君はできる子知ってるよ
Hey, guess what, I know you're totally capable, I know it
辛い時は 弱いくらいでちょうどいい
When it's tough, being a little weak is just right
あたし君の味方だよ mwah!
I'm always on your side, mwah!
お願い 君が欲しいの 名前を呼んでよ
Please, I want you so bad, call my name!
いつだって 会いに参上
Anytime, I'll come running to meet you
君はひとりか？ それは違う ひとりじゃない
Are you alone? That's not true, you're not alone!
もういいでしょ？
That's enough now, right?
ソロプレイはおしまいなんだっだったってば
I'm telling you, solo play is over!
君がどんなときも あたしそばにいるわ
No matter when, I'll always be by your side
いつも見守っているわ そうよ怖くないのよ
I'm always watching over you, that's right, don't be scared
mwah! お願い 君が欲しいの 慰めさせて
Mwah! Please, I want you so bad, let me comfort you
ベストフレンド 愛の才能で 泣いてくれるかい？
Best friend, with my knack for loving, won't you cry for me?
君の辛い 抱きしめたい ねえいいでしょ？
I wanna hold your pain tight, say yes, okay?
分け合って 乗り越えたいんだっだったってば
I'm telling you, I wanna share it and overcome it together!
mwah! お願い 君が欲しいの
Mwah! Please, I want you so bad
笑い飛ばして ホップ ステップ ジャンプ 最高で
Laugh it off, hop, step, jump, the absolute best!
分けてくれるかい？ 君にはもう辛い思い
Won't you share it with me? Your dark thoughts
もうさせたくない！ 寄り添って 救いたいんだっだったってば
I don't wanna let you feel them anymore! I wanna stay close and save you!
ねえあたし知ってるよ 君がひとり涙してるの知ってるよ
Hey, guess what, I know that you're all alone crying, I know it
グスングスン凹んでさ 弱音吐いてからいいんじゃない？
Sob-sobbing and feeling down, isn't it fine to vent your weakness?
ずっと一緒のとなりだって 何度だって受け止めてあげる
Being right next to you forever, I'll embrace you again and again
もう我慢しないで 出してってってってばー！
Don't hold it in anymore, let it all out, I'm telling you!
はーい！ということで、新衣装でーす！
Yay! So then, here's my new outfit!
みんな可愛いー？
Is it cute, everyone?
気になるとは思うけど、紹介は後で！
I know you're curious, but I'll introduce it later!
先にゲストの方と歌うよ！
First, I'm going to sing with our guest!
どうぞー！
Come on in!
GUEST 響咲リオナ
[Guest: Riona Hibiki]
僕らよ 始まれ
Let us begin.
青く 青く 果てまで
Far into the blue, to the ends of the earth.
眉の潜めを分けたバースデイ
A birthday where we share furrowed brows,
ホームシックにやられそうなバースデイ
a birthday nearly overcome by homesickness.
どこにいたって足りない 命はひとつじゃ足りない
Wherever we are, it's not enough; one life is just not enough.
まだ 羽ばたくのは未来で
Not yet, taking flight is for the future,
まだ 不思議な夢を見る
as I still dream strange dreams.
2人なら どこまでも行けると どうしてか信じたくなる
If it's the two of us, why do I want to believe we can go anywhere?
跳ねる鼓動 誰を呼ぶの ベルの音
A pounding heartbeat, calling to whom? The ringing bell,
そして待って 春夏秋冬 側自分次第
and wait, through the four seasons, it all depends on us.
あっという間に生まれる 祭りのライン
In an instant, the festive lineup is born,
嘘ね 災いも 笑い合おう 共に在ろう
no lie, let's laugh through misfortune and be together!
至ったって 不完全体 故に面白くなってきた
Though far from perfect, that's why it's getting exciting!
空腹のような声 空白に願い唱え
Voices like a ravenous hunger, chanting wishes into the void,
諦めつくされた世界を 君と2人占めに転げ回れ
in a world given up on, let's roll around taking it all for ourselves!
混ざり合い そして生まれ変わるような
Blending together, as if being reborn anew,
きっと僕らだけがなせる パレード
surely a parade that only we can create!
絶対証明したい進化論 才能開花したい絶頂時代
The theory of evolution we must prove, a golden era to bloom our talent!
どうなりたい？
What do you want to become?
架空も現実も幾重にも敷き詰め たがり 過去の惜別を煮詰めた勝手な哀歌に
Laying down layers of fiction and reality, crafting a selfish elegy of past farewells—
今はそこに君がいる 道になるわ 象徴 確信の夜
but now you are there, paving the way in this night of absolute certainty!
まだ眠れなき夜 行こうか
Through this sleepless night... shall we go?
僕らよ 始まれ
Let us begin.
青く 青く 果てまで
Far into the blue, to the ends of the earth.
至ったって 不完全体 故に面白くなってきた
Though far from perfect, that's why it's getting exciting!
空腹のような声 空白に願い唱え
Voices like a ravenous hunger, chanting wishes into the void,
諦めつくされた世界を 君と2人占めに転げ回れ
in a world given up on, let's roll around taking it all for ourselves!
混ざり合い そして生まれ変わるような
Blending together, as if being reborn anew,
きっと僕らこそがなせる パレード
surely a parade that only we can create!
完全体 美しき パレード
A fully realized, beautiful parade!
はい！というわけで、ゲストの前にちょっとね...
All right! Before moving on to our guest...
東北の方で地震があったみたいですが、大丈夫でしょうか？
It seems there was an earthquake in the Tohoku region. Is everyone okay?
東北の方、身の回りの安全を優先でお願いします！
Everyone in Tohoku, please prioritize your safety above all else!
気をつけるんだよー！ / 気をつけてください！
Please stay safe! / Please take care!
そして！次のゲストはリオナちゃんです！
And now, our next guest is Riona-chan!
FLOW GLOWのリーダー、響咲リオナです！よろしくお願いしまーす！
I'm Riona Hibiki, leader of FLOW GLOW! It's great to be here!
そして、そら先輩！お誕生日おめでとうございます！
And Sora-senpai, happy birthday!
ありがとうございますー！嬉しい！
Thank you so much! I'm so happy!
今日はね、最近めちゃくちゃ仲良しっていうのもあるし...
Today, since we've gotten super close lately...
あと、歌とダンスといえば、今はリオナちゃんってイメージがあって！
and when I think of singing and dancing, Riona-chan immediately comes to mind!
一緒に歌いたいと思って呼んじゃいました！
I really wanted to sing together, so I invited you!
本当に嬉しかったです、呼ばれたとき！超超嬉しい！
I was so happy when you invited me! Super happy!
そら先輩、新衣装じゃないですか！
Sora-senpai, isn't that a new outfit?!
めちゃくちゃ可愛い！ / ありがとうございます！
It's so cute! / Thank you so much!
どんな衣装なんですか？
What kind of outfit is it?
こちらはいですね、去年出したアルバムの『Palo Santo』のジャケットで使った衣装なんですけど
This is the outfit used on the cover of my album "Palo Santo" released last year,
実際にライブでも着たいと思って仕立てて...
and I had it tailor-made because I wanted to wear it in live performances too!
いただきました！
We got it!
あら、もうそんな、そらとむさんも「きゃー」って感じで...
Oh, isn't that making Soratomos go "Kyaa!" like that...
「きゃー」って感じになっちゃうかもしれない
They might end up going "Kyaa!"
じゃあ、あの、シロさんを見習って
Well then, taking a page from Shiro-san,
リオーナが来た意味をね、今から私やっていこうと思うんですけど
I'm going to show you the reason Riona came today!
ま、みんなもね、写真がいっぱい撮りたいと思うので
I'm sure everyone wants to take lots of photos,
リオーナ直伝のセクシーポーズ写真集！
so here's a sexy pose photoshoot direct from Riona!
おー、どうですか？ / やるやる！
Ooh, how's that? / Let's do it, let's do it!
スクショ大会？こんな... / 大会です！もうこれは
A screenshot tournament? Like this... / It's a tournament! Absolutely.
大会だった
A tournament, huh?
あの、セクシーなポーズを直伝してくれるので
Since she's going to teach us sexy poses,
それをね、そらとむさんに写真撮ってもらうという回で
this is a segment where Soratomos get to take pictures!
私はもう画面外で...
As for me, I'll just step off-screen...
え、何で！
Eh, why?!
あとで入ろうね / あ、オッケーです
Join in later, okay? / Ah, okay!
じゃあ、まず...
Alright then, first...
えー、やっぱリオーナと言えば、これですから
Um, when you think of Riona, it's gotta be this.
これできるかな、私
Can I even do this?
ちょっと足をこう... / 私できる？ちょっと...
Put your leg like this... / Can I do this? Wait...
色々アウト
So many things are wrong here!
これどうですか？こういうの / こういうのね
How's this? Something like this? / Like this, right?
でもリオーナはね、行きますからね
But Riona can go further!
あー！いいですね！いいですね！あーいいですね！
Ah! Nice, nice! Oh, that's great!
ちょっと右手を前に出しちゃったりして...
Maybe reach out your right hand a bit...
あー！いいですね！いいですね！
Ah! Nice! That's really nice!
あーちょっと...あーいい！うまい！
Ah, wait... Ah, great! So good!
あれ？そら先輩、セクシーの才能が...
Huh? Sora-senpai, your talent for being sexy...
かなりあるんじゃないですか？
...might actually be pretty high!
おー！素晴らしい！
Ooh! Wonderful!
え、あとはどうしようかな...
Um, what should I do next...
あ、やだ、いいの？それ
Oh my, wait, is that allowed?
そういうことじゃないの、セクシーって
That's not what sexy means!
ちょっと教える必要なかったですよ、これ！
Wait, I didn't even need to teach you!
うまっ！後ろからのアングルめっちゃいいな
So good! Wow, this angle from behind is amazing.
ちょっと！感心してないでよ
Hey! Stop just admiring it!
あ、ごめん
Ah, sorry!
なんかね、こういうのとかね。やっほーみたいな
Like, something like this, saying "Yaboo~"
後ろからの、イエーイ
And from behind, "Yay!"
あーいいですねいいですね！かわいい！
Ah, that's nice, that's nice! So cute!
色とりどりでめっちゃ綺麗ですね
It's so colorful and gorgeous!
そうなの！グラデーションが入っててかわいいんだよー
Right! It has this gradient that makes it so cute~
めっちゃかわいいー！
It's super cute!
え、じゃあ一緒に撮ってくれますか？
Oh, then will you pose with me?
もちろんだよー
Of course!
そらりおポーズ考えようって言ったのに全然考えられなかった
I said we'd think of a SoraRio pose, but I couldn't think of anything!
なんか、クマと...リオーナっぽいポーズが...
Like, a bear and... a pose that feels like Riona...
リオーナの公式ポーズがこれなんですけど
Riona's official pose is this one,
私はこうなんだよね / そう、だから...
and mine is like this. / Right, so...
ほぼ似てる / ほぼ一緒！
They're almost the same! / Almost identical!
クマと手を出す、こう！っていうのが
Making a bear and reaching out like this,
いいんじゃないかって思ってるんですけど、皆さんどうですか？
I think that works great! What do you all think?
そらりおポーズ！
The SoraRio Pose!
クマ伸ばし
Bear stretch!
暗鬼元伸ばし
Ankimoto stretch!
あ、あとあれですよ。最近私のこと飲んでるって本当ですか？
Oh, and also! Is it true you've been drinking me lately?
そう！
That's right!
リオーナ茶を！
Riona Tea!
貧血のリオーナ茶を！
Riona Tea for anemia!
すごく助かっています！
It's been a massive help!
本当ですか？じゃあもういつでも呼び出してください
Really? Then please call me anytime!
リオーナ座りに行くんで！
I'll come sit down as Riona!
ありがとうございます。そら先輩どうぞーって
Thank you! "Here you go, Sora-senpai~"
うわー！助かるー！
Woah! That saves me!
私助かるー！
That really helps me out!
いつでもね、供給しますんで
I'll keep supplying you anytime!
あ、ありがとうございます。じゃあいつでも呼んでくださいね / はーい！
Thank you! Call me whenever you need, okay? / Okay~!
あれ？あれ？リオーナ？
Huh? Wait, Riona?
あー！どうしよう！そら先輩助けてー！
Ahh! What do I do?! Sora-senpai, save me~!
助けてー！そら先輩！そら先輩ー！
Save me~! Sora-senpai! Sora-senpai~!
あーーー！
Ahhhhh~!
これ、みんな...
Wait, is everyone...
みんなそれをやっていくんだ！
Is everyone going to do that?!
みんなそれをやっていくんだ
So everyone is going to do that!
さあ！
Alright then!
でもね、リオーナちゃんともね本当に仲が良くて、いっつもね、よく会うんですけど
But you know, I'm really close with Riona-chan, we meet up all the time,
普段と変わらない、かわちい感じでしたね
and she was super cute today just like always!
私消えましたね、ごめんなさい
Oh, I disappeared for a second there, sorry!
お水を飲みに行ってました
I just stepped away to drink some water.
はい！
Alright!
というわけで
Moving on!
続いてのゲストは、もう誰だか分かるよね？
Our next guest... you all know who it is, right?
この人です！
It's this person!
GUEST 風真いろは
[Guest: Kazama Iroha]
ヒビカセ
[Song: Hibikase]
真夜中に告ぐ 音の警告
Signaling in the dead of night, a warning of sound
協和音に酔う 午前0時
Drunk on harmonic sound at midnight
あなたが触れる 光増す熱
The warmth grows brighter at your touch
指先に踊らされ
Dancing at your fingertips
感覚 即 体感
Sensation instantly becomes real
寝静まる夜 2人だけの蜜
In the quiet night, sweet nectar just for us
体感 即 快感
Experience instantly becomes pleasure
重なる波形に魅了されていく
Captivated by the overlapping waveforms
忘れないでね
Don't forget me,
わたしの声を
my voice.
画面越しでいい
Even if it's through a screen,
ちゃんと愛して
love me properly.
ヴァーチャルだって
Don't push me away
突き放さないで
just because I'm virtual.
あなたの音に
I still want to drown
まだ溺れていたい
in your sounds.
覚えていてね
Please remember
わたしの声を
my voice.
あなたがくれた
Everything about this body
この身すべてを
that you gave me.
見つめ合う
Locking eyes,
あなたと二人
just the two of us,
重ねた息と
with our overlapped breaths
音とヒビカセ
and sounds echoing out.
真夜中に問う 冷え切った熱
In the middle of the night, asking about the chilled heat,
待ち続けてる 午前零時
waiting continuously for midnight.
鏡映しに 飽和していく
Saturated in the mirror reflection,
知らない音が伝う
an unfamiliar sound travels.
感覚 即 体感
Perception immediately becomes experience.
寝静まる夜と息遣い揃う
Breathing in sync with the quiet night.
体感 即 快感
Experience immediately becomes pleasure.
錆びたロジック「今一度」を焦がれる
Longing for a rusted logic "once more".
忘れないでね
Don't forget me,
わたしの声を
my voice.
次元も超えて
A signal sent flying,
飛ばすシグナル
even crossing dimensions.
ヴァーチャルだななんて
Don't say things like
言わないで
"It's just virtual."
あなたの音に
I still want to be loved
まだ愛されていたい
by your sounds.
覚えていてね
Please remember
わたしの声を
my voice.
あなたがくれた
Everything about this body
この身すべてを
that you gave me.
言の葉と初の音が交わる
Words and first notes intersect,
この息と音とヒビカセ
letting these breaths and sounds echo.
あぁ あなたの生んだ音に
Ah, with the music you birthed,
あぁ ただ恋をしていたの
Ah, I was simply in love.
悲しみ 怒り 歓心 すべて 打ち鳴らす
Sadness, anger, interest, ringing them all out!
絶え絶え叫ぶ 声連ねる
Faintly shouting, intertwining voices,
熱増せる 愛で包みつやめく
wrapped in increasing heat and love, glistening.
絶え絶え叫ぶ 声連ねる
Faintly shouting, intertwining voices,
熱増せる 愛で包みつやめく
wrapped in increasing heat and love, glistening.
魅了されていく
Becoming fascinated...
忘れないでね
Don't forget me,
わたしの声を
my voice.
画面越しでいい
Even if it's through a screen,
ちゃんと愛して
love me properly.
ヴァーチャルだって
Don't push me away
突き放さないで
just because I'm virtual.
あなたの音に
I still want to drown
まだ溺れていたい
in your sounds.
覚えていてね
Please remember
わたしの声を
my voice.
あなたがくれた
Everything about this body
この身すべてを
that you gave me.
見つめ合う
Locking eyes,
あなたと二人
just the two of us,
重ねた息と
with our overlapped breaths
音をヒビカセ
and sounds echoing out.
あなたの初の音
Your first notes,
この声聴かせ
let me hear this voice,
オトヒビカセ
let the sounds echo out!
はい！というわけで最後のゲストは、いろはちゃんです！
All right! And so, our final guest is Iroha-chan!
イェーイ！ホロックスの、強い、イケメン、速い、かっこいい、ん〜なんかすごい、風真いろはでーす！
Yay! I'm holoX's strong, handsome, fast, cool, um... super awesome Kazama Iroha~!
おかしいな... おかしいな...
That's strange... / That's strange...
そら先輩！ 何？
Sora-senpai! / What is it?
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
おかしいな... 何がおかしいんだい？
That's strange... / What's strange?
リハーサル日まではあんなにメロついてくれてたのに...
Up until rehearsal day, you were so head over heels for me...
すごいじゃん！きっ、今日のために整えてくれたってこと？
That's amazing! Y-You mean you prepared all this just for today?
今日のために、ちょっと整えさせていただきまして...
Just for today, I made sure to prepare myself...
あ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you very much!
コメント欄のみんなもあんなにメロついてくれてたのに、今日は全然メロついてない！
Everyone in the comments was so head over heels for me too, but today no one is at all!
いやいや、そんなことなかったよ！「かっこいい、二人とも」って書いてあったよ！
No, no, that's not true! They wrote "Both of you are so cool!"
本当ですか？本当？え、ちょっともう一回見たいから「かっこいい」って書いて！
Really? Truly? Eh, I want to see it again, so write "cool"!
みんな「かっこいい」って書いて！
Everyone, write "cool"!
あ、「可愛い、可愛い、可愛い」... 可愛いは当たり前じゃん！
Ah, "cute, cute, cute"... Being cute is obvious!
あ、そうだよね、そうだよね。
Ah, right, right.
ござるちゃんはいつでも可愛い！ ほら、そら先輩、「かっこいい、かっこいい」って！
Gozaru-chan is always cute! / Look, Sora-senpai, they're saying "cool, cool"!
あ、ありがとう！たとえ「かっこいい」が義務だとしても風真いろはは嬉しいぞ！
Ah, thank you! Even if saying "cool" is an obligation, Kazama Iroha is happy!
1人でも記念配信で歌ってたけど、すごく似合ってたから一緒に歌いたいなと思って呼び出しちゃいました！
You sang it in your solo anniversary stream too, and it suited you so well that I wanted to sing it together and invited you!
嬉しい！嬉しくて、嬉しくて死んでしまう...
I'm so happy! I'm so happy, I'm gonna die...
生きて！生きて！あ、生きてますよ！良かった良かった。
Live! Live! Ah, she's alive! Thank goodness.
いやでも感無量...！やっぱそら先輩と言えば、ボカロがめっちゃ似合うなーって思ってたんで...
I'm just so overwhelmed with emotion...! After all, when I think of Sora-senpai, Vocaloid songs suit you so well...
いつかやってくれないかなってオタクとして思ってたんですけど、まさか自分がゲストとして呼んでもらえるなんて...！こんなありがたいことがあっていいのか...！
As a fan, I used to hope you'd cover it someday, but to think I'd be invited as a guest...! Is it really okay for something so wonderful to happen...!
でも、一緒に2人で歌ったことがなかったから歌ってみたくて。
But since we've never sung together as a duo, I really wanted to try it.
確かに！ホシマティックだと結構対になってること多いんですけどね。
That's true! In Hoshimatic, we're paired up quite a bit though.
フェスとかでも歌ったけど3人とかだったから、デュエットってやったことなくて。
We've sung at festivals, but that was in trios, so we've never done a duet.
確かに！ねー！ありがたいお話でございます、本当に。
Indeed! I know! I'm really grateful for this opportunity.
本当にこちらこそ！貴重な体験を... いやー、こちらこそありがとうございました、本当に！
No, the pleasure is all mine! Such a valuable experience... Thank you so much!
はい。それにしても...
Yes. Anyway...
今日これ、新衣装なんですよね！
Today is the reveal of your new outfit, right!
そうなんですよ、新衣装なんですよ！どう？
That's right, it's a new outfit! How is it?
いやちょっと、リオンさんが結構際どいことをやっていたんですけど...
Well, Rion was doing some pretty risky things earlier...
やはりね、オタクとして1個よろしいでしょうか？
As an otaku, may I ask one thing?
やはりオタクというものはですね、一肌脱いだ姿がすごい気になるというものでございまして...
As an otaku, I'm really curious about what's underneath...
この隠されている純白が、この姿が見れるのかっていうのがすごく気になっておりまして...
I'm really wondering if we'll get to see the pure white underlayer...
だってこの下の清楚感あふれるこれ、絶対みんな気になるでしょ？オタクとして気になりますよ！
I mean, everyone must be curious about this pure vibe underneath, right? As an otaku, I care!
そうですよね！でも、この配信の中では、ちょっとまだ見せられないかな。
Right! But I can't really show it during this stream just yet.
え、もしや、それは脱ぐということでござるか？
Wait, does that mean you'll take it off?
この配信の中では見せることはないんだけど、メン限に入れ！メン限だったら見れるかもしれないぞ！
I won't show it here, but join the members-only stream! You might see it there!
はい。楽しみにしておりますので。
Alright. I'm really looking forward to it.
メン限に入れ？入れ？強制（笑）
"Join members-only? Join?" So pushy!
これが、取れた姿が見れるんですよね！この後も楽しみにさせてもらいますよ！
So we can see what it looks like taken off! I'll be looking forward to what comes next!
はーい！というわけで、そら先輩、この後も全然続くと思うんですけど、頑張ってください！
Okay! So Sora-senpai, I know there's still a lot more to come, so good luck!
頑張るよ～！
I'll do my best~!
プロとしてお待ちしておりますので。そうね、また後で。
I'll be waiting for you as a pro. Yeah, see you later.
プロの世界に引き込まれてしまう！あー！上品だからお尻は出さないでー！
I'm getting dragged into the pro world! Ahh! Keep it classy, don't show your butt!
ありがとう、ありがとう。未来で待っててくれ。指なんだ！
Thank you, thank you. Wait for me in the future. It's just a finger!
さて、何、「また後で」ってどういうことなんでしょうかね？
Now then, what does "see you later" mean?
プロとして何のプロなんでしょうか？気になる方、配信に来てもらえたら嬉しいなと思います。
What kind of "pro" is she referring to? If you're curious, please come to the stream.
さて、ちょっと待ってくださいね。いよいよ終盤戦です。
Now, please wait a moment. It's finally time for the home stretch.
お水タイム！
Water time!
いよいよ終盤戦なんですけど、最後まで盛り上がっていってください！
We're in the final stretch, so please keep the energy going until the end!
もしかしたら、あの子が来ちゃうかもね。聞いてください、「プレイ」。
Maybe that person will show up too. Please listen, "Play".
プレイ
[Song: Play]
ちょけろ ちょけろ
Mess around, mess around
さぁ図に乗って いい加減にしろって
Go on, get carried away, tell me to cut it out
やめらんないねぇ どうしようもねぇ
Can't stop, can't help it
言い訳なら後で考えてくれてやる
If you want an excuse, I'll think of one for you later
王道とかくだらねぇな毎回
The royal road is stupid every single time
自意識過剰なやつ徘徊
Self-conscious fools wandering around
みんなが右往左往する間に こちとら地に足つけてきたぜ ハイハイ
While everyone's running in circles, I've kept my feet on the ground, yeah yeah
どうした？みんな浮かない顔して
What's wrong? Everyone's looking down
絵空事大歓迎よ
Pipe dreams are more than welcome
現実味ねぇよ
There's no sense of reality
早く楽になりたい？
Want to be put at ease soon?
いつでもいいよ
Anytime is fine
おねんねさせたれ
Go put them to sleep
Nothing to do with you
ちょけろ ちょけろ
Mess around, mess around
さぁ図に乗って いい加減にしろって
Go on, get carried away, tell me to cut it out
やめらんないねぇ
Can't stop
はぜろ はぜろ
Burst open, burst open
責任だってとるよ 墓場までは
I'll take responsibility, but only till the grave
堂々とだけさせてくれよ
Just let me act with confidence
こちとらマイペースなトラブルメーカー
I'm a my-pace trouble maker
取扱説明書 隅から隅まで読んでおきな
Read the instruction manual from cover to cover
ヒヤッとしたってなぜか ニヤッとしちゃうのおかしいな
Even when scared, why do I end up smirking? It's weird
とめろ とめろ とめろ とめろ
Stop it, stop it, stop it, stop it
絵空事も大歓迎よ
Pipe dreams are more than welcome too
現実味ねぇよ
There's no sense of reality
早く楽になりたい？
Want to be put at ease soon?
いつでもいいよ
Anytime is fine
おねんねさせたれ
Go put them to sleep
Nothing to do with you
押せよ そのリセットボタン
Press it, that reset button
消せよ お前のその価値観
Erase it, your sense of values
どうせ 何度も 元に戻せるなら
If it can be restored over and over anyway
指くわえて見てるだけじゃ つまらないやいや
Just watching with a finger in your mouth is boring
So I'm ready
思いっきり 前ノリ気味
Leaning forward with all my might
止まる気ない アクセルベタ踏み
No intention to stop, pedal to the metal
ねぇ Are you kidding? ねぇ Are you kidding?
Hey, are you kidding? Hey, are you kidding?
はい ちょ待って ここでストップ Return to the start
Okay, wait a sec, stop here, return to the start
ぜっていやべーよ！ 話がちげーぞ！
That's definitely crazy! That's not what was agreed on!
早く楽になりたい？
Want to be put at ease soon?
いつでもいいよ
Anytime is fine
おねんねさせたれ
Go put them to sleep
Nothing can do it, too!
押せよ そのリセットボタン
Press that reset button.
消せよ マイナスの価値観
Erase those negative values.
本当はもう 二度と戻ってこれないから
Because in truth, we can never go back again,
調子に乗せて 酔わせてみるのが
so maybe it's just easier to get carried away, drunk on it,
楽でいいのかもしれないな
and roll with it.
はい！ ありがとうございました！
Yes! Thank you so much!
この曲『トレイ』を歌わせていただきました！
I performed the song "Torei"!
そして この曲ではなんと サングラスをかけたあんきもがやってきました！
And for this song, Ankiimo came out wearing sunglasses!
どうしてサングラス？
Why the sunglasses?
わぁ、取れたー！
Whoa, they came off!
遊ばないの！ はい！
Don't play with them! Alright!
と言うわけで久々にね あんきもと一緒に なんか踊った気がするんだけど どう？
Anyway, it feels like it's been a while since I danced with Ankiimo. How was it?
5人目のゲスト あんきもです！
Our fifth guest is Ankiimo!
イエーイ！
Yay!
ある意味シークレットだった(笑) めっちゃ踊るじゃん！
In a way, he was a secret guest! Look at him dance!
そしてね、そんな感じで
And so, with that said...
まだね 最後にね 実はお披露目もあるんだけど
While we still have one final reveal at the end,
ここでね まず恒例のおらせが たくさんあるので
first, we have a lot of our usual announcements,
ここからはあんきもと一緒に 告知していくね！
so from here on, Ankiimo and I will share the announcements together!
聞いてください！ まずはこちら！
Please listen! First up is this!
ときのそら 誕生日記念2026 グッズです！
Tokino Sora Birthday Celebration 2026 merchandise!
順番に紹介していくよ！
I'll introduce them one by one!
まずはこちら！
First up, this one!
Dream!そらとも法被！ イラストはおるだん先生です！
"Dream! Soratomo Happi"! Illustration by Orudan-sensei!
テーマは「ライブをしてる私」ということで なんとあんきももいっぱいいるんだよ！
The theme is "Me performing live," and look, there are lots of Ankiimos too!
ね！ あの 今までオリジナル法被自体は
Right? Until now, we've had original happi coats
1st LIVEとかで出たことはあるんですけど
released for things like the 1st Live and such,
自分でオリジナルで作るの は初めてだったので
but this is the first time I've designed an original one myself,
ぜひライブで着てきてほしいなと思って作りました！
so I made it hoping you'll wear it to concerts!
ぜひぜひ みんな楽しんでくださいね！
Please, everyone, enjoy it!
ライブに来てください！
Please come to the live concert!
続いてはこちら！
Next is this!
「お部屋でのんびり」ワイドラバーマット！
"Relaxing in My Room" Wide Rubber Mat!
イエーイ！ イラストはシワスタカシ先生です！
Yay! Illustration by Shiwasu Takashi-sensei!
テーマは「部屋でファンレターを読んでいる私」で
The theme is "Me reading fan letters in my room,"
こちらね ホロカのやつにね ちょうどいいサイズになってるので
and it's just the right size for Holoca cards,
ホロカを遊ぶ方 ぜひぜひ
so for those who play Holoca, by all means
一緒にね 持っていって遊んでもらえたら嬉しいなと思います！
I'd be happy if you take it with you to play!
続いてはこちら！
Next is this!
そらとおそろいスマホリング！
"Matching with Sora Smartphone Ring"!
ということでね 前回販売したDJ衣装パーカーと
So, this shares its design with
デザインが一緒なので
the DJ outfit hoodie sold last time,
それと一緒に合わせて スマホも私とおそろっちみたいにしませんか？
so why not match your smartphone with me as well?
という感じです！
That's the concept!
そして続いてはこちら！
And next up is this!
そらザウルスなりきりそらちゃんぬいぐるみ！
"Sorasaurus Cosplay Sora-chan Plushie"!
みんな...
Everyone...
みんながあまりにもさ 「そらザウルスそらザウルス」って言うからさ
Because everyone kept saying "Sorasaurus, Sorasaurus,"
でも そらザウルス自体を言うのはちょっと恥ずかしかったから
but making a straight-up Sorasaurus plush felt a bit embarrassing,
そらちゃんぬいぐるみ... 私が着ていることにする なりきりぬいぐるみ にしました！
so I made it a plushie of Sora-chan wearing a cosplay outfit!
しかもね あのね 「何？そらザウルス」って思う人！
Plus, for those wondering, "What's a Sorasaurus?"
これ 取ると... フードが取れると Pinkの衣装を着てる私みたいになるので
if you remove the hood, it looks like me wearing my pink outfit!
ぜひぜひ フードを取り外して可愛く持ち歩いてくれてもいいんじゃないかなと思います！
So feel free to take the hood off and carry it around cutely!
そして最後はこちら！
And finally, this!
ASMRボイス！
ASMR Voice!
ボイスタイトル「届いているよ、きみの応援」ということで
Voice title: "Your Cheer Has Reached Me."
部屋でファンレターを読んでいるシチュエーションになっておりますので
It's set in a situation where I'm reading fan letters in my room,
ぜひぜひ皆さん どんな風にファンレター読んでるのかなと想像しながら聴いてもらえたら嬉しいです！
so I hope you'll listen while imagining how I read your letters!
そして フルセット購入特典はこちら！
And here is the Full Set Purchase Bonus!
直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードと
A postcard with a handwritten signature & foil-stamped message,
特典ボイス ボイスタイトルは「誕生日を迎えて」になります！
and a bonus voice titled "Welcoming My Birthday"!
というわけでですね 皆さん急がなくても大丈夫です！
So everyone, you don't need to rush!
数量限定ではございませんので
It's not limited in quantity,
皆さん全員分のサインを書かせていただきます！
so I will sign for every single one of you!
いくらでも書きますので ぜひぜひ皆さん！
I'll write as many as needed, so please!
たくさんの人にグッズを買ってもらえたら 私はとっても...
If many people buy the merch, I'll be very...
そらっち大喜び！ なので
Soracchi will be overjoyed! So...
よろしくお願いいたします！
Thank you so much in advance!
以上 ときのそら 誕生日記念2026グッズでした！
That's all for the Tokino Sora Birthday Celebration 2026 merch!
みんなよろしくね！
Thank you, everyone!
続いてのお知らせはこちら！
Next announcement is this!
大急ぎで駆け足で！ 11月ワンマンライブの
In a big hurry! For the November solo concert,
「ときのそら 生誕記念先行チケット販売」開始！
"Tokino Sora Birthday Celebration Advance Ticket Sales" start!
ということで ぴあアリーナの先行チケットが
So advance tickets for Pia Arena
本日から始まっております！
have started today!
「ファンクラブに入ってる人しかできないんじゃないか」って思ってた人！
For those who thought "Isn't it only for Fan Club members?",
本日から一般で皆さんも販売が開始されておりますので
general sales for everyone have also started today,
ぜひぜひ！もう12時から開始されております！
so please! It started at 12:00!
応募していただけたら嬉しいです！
I'd be happy if you apply!
みんなでぴあアリーナで ライブ楽しもう！
Let's enjoy the live at Pia Arena together!
さらにこちら！
Furthermore, this!
現地チケットの特典でもらえるホロカのお披露目！ これもお披露目でございました！
The reveal of the Holoca card you get as a venue ticket bonus! This was also a reveal!
ライブの来場者特典として限定ホロカが1枚配られます！
As a venue visitor bonus, 1 limited Holoca card will be given out!
全2種類のうち1枚をランダムでお渡しするのですが
You'll get 1 random card out of 2 types,
そちらの1枚を公開です！
and we are revealing 1 of those cards!
私が描き下ろすということで もう1個の方は...
Since I drew this one, as for the other one...
ぜひこちらの方でちょっと...
Please, with this one...
満足していただけないでしょうか？
Won't you be satisfied with this?
革新的なライブを記念して、こちら！
And to commemorate the anniversary live, this!
スペシャルテレビCM放送決定！ということで
Special TV CM broadcast decided! So...
本日の22時半から23時のあいだで Tokyo MXさんの
Today between 22:30 and 23:00 on Tokyo MX...
ところで流れます。一度だけなので
it will air. It's only once,
ぜひ見てくれると嬉しいなと思いますよ。よろしくお願いします！
so I'd be happy if you watched it. Please check it out!
そしてそして！最後のお知らせがこちら！
And next, next! The final announcement is this!
お待たせしました！こちらです！新曲「決意のソラへ」です！
Thank you for waiting! Here it is! New song "To the Sky of Determination"!
私的にはなんあエモい感じの曲とかね、泣き曲かなって思ったんだけど
For me, I thought it was an emotional song or a tearjerker,
でもディレクターさん的には泣き曲とかエモとかそういう感じじゃない、熱い曲
but according to the director, it's not a tearjerker or emotional, but a passionate song,
オープニングに相応しい感じの、熱い曲を作ったつもりみたいなことを言っていたので
like an opening theme, a passionate song they intended to create, so...
このあとね、MVがプレミア公開も予定されているので
After this, the MV premiere release is scheduled,
各種音楽サイトでも配信もされています。ぜひたくさん聴いてもらえたら嬉しいです！
and it's also available on various music sites. I'd be happy if you listened to it a lot!
はい、というわけでね、とっても楽しかったんですけど、いかがだったでしょうか？
Alright then, I had so much fun, but how was it for you?
告知がね、洪水のやってきたと思うので、あとでみんな確認してもらえると嬉しいなと思います
The announcements came like a flood, so I hope everyone checks them later!
えー、そしてですね、本公演は21時半からアフターライブがあるんですけど
And also, after this main stream, at 21:30 there's an after-live,
スペシャルあん肝がね、なんと見れるかもしれないんだって。スペシャルだよ、スペシャル！
and you might get to see a special Ankimo! It's special, special!
このサングラスあん肝もスペシャルではあるんだけど、さらにスペシャルなあん肝が見れるかもしれない
This sunglasses Ankimo is special too, but you might see an even more special Ankimo!
そしてね、さっきも言いました、この放送では
And as I said earlier, in this broadcast...
ちょっとまだ脱げないかなーって言ってたもの、ありますよね？
there was something I said "maybe I can't take off yet", right?
いろんな撮影会しましょう！
Let's have various photo sessions!
というわけで、ここまで付き合ってくれてありがとう！あん肝、バイバイ！
So, thank you for staying with us until now! Ankimo, bye-bye!
サングラス似合ってたぞ！
The sunglasses looked good on you!
みんな吸い込まれていく
Everyone is getting sucked in...
はい、というわけでね、皆さん...
Alright then, everyone...
いかがだったでしょうか？
How was it?
こんなにね、いつもの情報の洪水が起こっていると思うんですが
There's such a flood of information as usual,
ぜひぜひ皆さん、あとで見てもらえたら嬉しいです
so I hope everyone checks it out later!
最後はですね、これだけ「決意のソラへ」と言っておいて歌わないのはどうかなと思いますので
Lastly, after talking so much about "To the Sky of Determination", I can't just not sing it,
新曲で締めたいと思います！
so I'd like to end with this new song!
それでは聴いてください。「決意のソラへ」
Please listen: "To the Sky of Determination".
一度きりの私の物語には
In my story that happens only once,
運命を超えて煌めくんだ
it will shine beyond fate.
行こう！
Let's go!
みんな、本日はありがとうございましたー！とっても楽しかったー！
Everyone, thank you so much for today! It was so much fun!
ねぇ 私より私のことを 分かってくれる キミの存在が
Your existence, understanding me better than I understand myself,
臆病で泣き虫な心に 勇気と言う魔法をかけたの
cast a spell called courage on my timid, crybaby heart.
チクタク 時計の針だけが進む
Tick-tock, only the hands of the clock advance.
立ち止まってちゃダメだ
I must not stand still.
それ転び八起きがお決まりでしょ
Falling down and getting back up is standard, right?
一つ一つ重ねてきた 大切なアルバムをめくるように
One by one we built them up, like flipping through a precious album.
一つ一つ叶えてきた今日まで
One by one we fulfilled them up to today,
その全てにキミがいてくれた
and in all of it, you were there for me.
終わりのない夢を
An endless dream...
ずっと ずっと ずっと ずっと 追いかけて行こう
let's keep chasing it forever and ever!
行こう！
Let's go!
Xのトレンド入りも果たしたそうで、ありがとうございます！
It seems we made it onto X trends too, thank you so much!
ねぇ ここで笑い合えることが 何よりも大事な真実
Hey, being able to laugh together here is the truth that matters above all else.
チクチクいたずらなハートが痛む
Tick-tick, my mischievous heart aches.
空回り空回り思考回路フル回転でよーいどん
Spinning in circles, thought circuits at full speed—ready, set, go!
泣いて 泣いて 泣いた夜も
Even on nights I cried, cried, and cried,
大切な人生のストーリーだから
it's a story of my precious life...
夢を 夢で 終わらせたくないんだ
I don't want to let my dreams end as just dreams,
まだ見ぬ景色を
to see the scenery
見に行こうよ
we've yet to see, let's go!
もっと もっと
More and more,
輝いて
shining bright,
高く 高く
higher and higher,
飛び立とう
let's take flight,
奇跡さえも超えて
surpassing even miracles!
皆さん たくさんのコメント ありがとうございます！
Everyone, thank you so much for all your comments!
一つ 一つ 重ねてきた
One by one, we've gathered memories
未来地図のページをめくるように
like turning the pages of a map to the future.
泣いて 泣いて 泣いた夜も
Even the nights I cried and cried,
大切な人生のストーリーだから
are precious stories of my life.
夢を 夢で 終わらせたくないんだ
I don't want to let my dreams end as just dreams,
まだ見ぬ景色を 見に行こうよ
let's go see the scenery we've yet to see.
終わりのない歌を
I'll deliver this endless song
キミに キミに キミへとお届け
to you, to you, to you!
ずっと ずっと 誓うの
I promise, forever and ever,
決意のソラへ
towards the sky of determination,
行こう
let's go!
本当にみんなのおかげで最高のお披露目誕生日になりました！
Thanks to everyone, this became the best birthday showcase ever!
みんなのこと大好きだよ！
I love you all so much!
アフターライブも来てね！
Be sure to come to the after-live stream too!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!